Joseph Bannerman

910-789-0353 josephagbannerman@gmail.com Github: Bannermanj 22415 Market Street Apt 1407 Cornelius, NC 28031

Profile

Web developer with experience in Javascript and Python. Of these languages the frameworks that I use or am familiar with are the following: Django, Express, React and Flask. I've been developing in Python for over 3 years using Flask and Django. I've been working with MERN for around 3 years as well. I love building things!

Experience

LEAD WEB DEVELOPER, VENTURE TITLE, CHARLOTTE, NC - DEC 2018- PRESENT

Developed a large isomorphic application using React.js, Next.js, Node and MongoDB(Atlas) with the anticipated use of thousands of users. Worked with a small agile team and taught coworkers ES6 and React. Developed several Express API's for various internal and external, company marketing and real estate sites. Ensured mobile first design practices for projects. Developed a marketing/video aggregator site that accompanied company video productions. Migrated all web applications to either AWS Lambda serverless or Next.js Now. Created a micro-service in Python Flask for a Google Calendar API live calendar feature.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER, DAVIDSON COLLEGE, DAVIDSON, NC - JUL 2017- JAN 2019

Developed automation scripts for repeatable tasks and tests using Selenium and Python. Took part in several agile scrum sprints to align project needs with the needs of end-users and the product owner. Worked with the team to develop a backend for a college-wide faculty course scheduler in Django with a React frontend. Developed a course scheduler using Node/Express and React, that takes in course data from a form and returns an eligible classroom for that time after running through an algorithm. Developed a laptop kiosk dashboard to highlight student usage data in ES6 and React. Made sure that key college websites were WCAG 2.0 AA compliant. Added two factor Duo authentication to add an extra layer of security to high risks applications and created a Duo portal for faculty enrollment. Recently began working on a campus wide API project written in Node/Express and GraphQL.

STUDENT/JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER, EAST CAROLINA UNIVERSITY COLLEGE STAR, GREENVILLE, NC – AUG 16 - JUN 17

Completed front end module edits of the CollegeStar Rails site. Performed database migrations and integrated Javascript audio for playback within the modules. Worked with the Lead Developer to implement Google Analytics to track unique visitors and worksheet downloads. Wrote Rspec tests to check portions of the users authorization within the Rails site.

INTERN MOBILE DEVELOPER, FRESH DIRECT, LONG ISLAND CITY, NEW YORK - JUN 16-AUG 16

Wrote unit tests for the newly released FoodKick mobile application using Xamarin. Created a separate test that took screenshots of the application at different intervals throughout the day to reveal if products were displaying at their appropriate times. Attended daily standup meetings with discussions about Jira and Jenkins tasks. Ate a bunch of awesome food!

STUDENT- CODING DOJO IMMERSIVE CODING BOOTCAMP, ONLINE, JUL 16-OC T 16

Learned front end developer skills such as Javascript, SASS, Bootstrap and jQuery. Also completed the Python section of the course which contained the frameworks Flask and Django as well as other necessary components of full stack development. Completed a series of small mobile applications in Swift for iPhone as part of the iOS section.

INTERN TECHNICAL WRITER, EAST CAROLINA OFFICE OF FACULTY EXCELLENCE – 2014-2015

Marketed the office's events through social media using tools such as Hootsuite. Worked with the graphic design team in creating digital and physical handouts.

Education

East Carolina University – BA English, Certificate of Business & Technical Communication – May 2017

Skills

My skills include technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jest, React, Next.js, Gatsby, Express, Node.js, Selenium, Postgres, MySQL, Sqlite, Django, DRF, and Flask. I also have a small amount of experience in mobile development using Java and Android Studio as well as Swift and Xcode, with a primary focus in Xcode for iPhone development.